Nick Forte

Data Analyst | Business Analyst

(615) 400-0901 | fortenw@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

ABOUT ME

Accomplished professional with 12+ years of work experience transitioning into Data Analytics. Analytical thinker and resourceful problem-solver who enjoys exploring, interpreting, and transforming data to paint a clear picture or tell an informative story. Effective communicator who listens proactively and asks problem questions to fully understand true needs. Enjoys performing detailed research and analysis with the goal of increasing efficiency and supporting decision-makers. Seeking an opportunity to continue learning and further grow my skills in a Data Analyst position.

SKILLS

- Data Analysis: Excel (Pivot Tables, V-Lookup), SQL (PostgreSQL), Python (Jupyter Notebooks)
- Data Visualization: Power BI, Tableau
- Microsoft: Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook
- Other: Git/GitHub, Agile Methodology, Kanban Boards, Google Sheets, Slack, Zoom

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

Jan 2022 – Present, Nashville Software School – Nashville, TN Data Analytics Apprentice

Full-time program using statistical reasoning through hands-on training in Python, SQL, Excel, Tableau, and Power BI with a focus on data storytelling, building reports, and creating dashboards.

PROJECTS

- <u>Nashville City Cemetery</u> (Excel): Cleaned and explored dataset on burials at the Nashville City Cemetery from 1846 to 1979 to find interesting facts for marketing materials for the cemetery. Created visualizations on age at death, by race, number of burials by year, common causes of death, and more
- App Trader (SQL, Excel): Cleaned, explored, and analyzed data from the Apple App Store and Google Play Store. Visualized and presented data-based investment recommendations on the top 10 most profitable apps in both app stores, as well as what genres, price ranges, and content ratings of aps tend to be the most profitable
- <u>Lahman Baseball</u> (SQL): Class team project requiring use of an ERD to assist with linking multiple data sheets to find answers to several baseball-related statistics
- Nashville Traffic Accidents (Excel, Power BI): Cleaned and explored data from Nashville.gov website to create a dashboard illustrating trends and patterns in Nashville traffic accidents from 2015 to 2022

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jan 2018 – Present, Forte Building Group – Brentwood, TN Assistant Project Manager

- Assist in pre-construction planning, homeowner & design collaboration, and construction management of custom, multi-million-dollar homes, and substantial renovations & additions
- Pre-Construction Planning: Review plans & specifications; Perform quantity take-offs; Develop scopes of work & review bids; Coordinate selection allowances
- Homeowner & Design Collaboration: Communicate selection timelines & priorities; Coordinate selection samples, quotes, approvals, & purchasing; Handle homeowner and design meetings, and checkpoint walkthroughs
- Construction Management: Job site supervision, quality control, and coordination of to-do lists;
 Update construction schedules, record daily logs and progress photos; Review shop drawings

and construction documents; Order, schedule, and handle material deliveries with vendors; Code invoices and manage change orders; Apply for permits and coordinate inspections

Sept 2012 – Sept 2017, HCTec – Brentwood, TN Healthcare IT Recruiter

- Supported IT staffing needs of healthcare clients across the United States, including many of the largest health systems in the nation, as well as regional health systems and stand-alone hospitals
- Identified, recruited, and successfully placed 80+ candidates in contract, contract-to-hire, and direct hire FTE roles, across all levels of IT, ranging from entry-level Help Desk positions to Sr. Program Manager and Director-level roles
- Single-handedly staffed an entire team of Clinical Engineers for a 12-month project to implement Capsule BMDI software for a 5-hospital system
- Responsible for full recruitment life cycle:
 - Sourcing and screening of candidates
 - Hourly rate/salary negotiation
 - o Preparation of client submittals
 - Scheduling and coordinating phone/video/in-person interviews
 - o Candidate follow-up throughout the interview/hiring process

Jan 2011 – Aug 2012, Snodgrass-King Dental Associates – Franklin, TN Treatment Coordinator/Human Resources

- Served as oral surgery treatment coordinator while assisting with HR and Payroll duties at main branch of this company dedicated to serving the dental needs of children as well as adults with 4 locations across Middle Tennessee
- Coordinated with all departments, including pediatric dentistry, adult dentistry and orthodontics, to provide proper treatment and make the oral surgery process as effortless as possible for patients and their families

Sept 2010 – April 2011, Personal Best Fitness – Brentwood, TN Certified Personal Trainer

- Worked as a Personal Trainer, interviewing and assessing new clients and developing customized fitness plans aimed at fulfilling the clients' goals
- Recruited new clients and developed and implemented a "New You" marketing program
- Developed strong referral base with Business Networking International referral group

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Nashville Software School

Data Analytics Bootcamp Certification (Expected Graduation April 2022)

Vanderbilt University

Bachelor of Science, Human & Organizational Development Leadership & Organizational Effectiveness Track